Let us now complete the week on image and video compression, by just a very brief
现在 作为本周图像和视频压缩课程的结束
description of run-length coding. Run-length coding is very useful for,
我们来简要的描述一下游程编码 通常来说
normally, when we, when I encode binary images.
游程编码在编码二值图像的时候非常的有用
So let's just draw a binary image. And then we have a box to illustrate
让我们画一幅二值图像 用一个框来表示
that. Let's assume we have an object here that
假如这里有一个特定灰度值的物体
has a certain grade value. And we only have two grade values.
这幅图中我们只使用两种灰度值
Let's say, 100 in the background, and. 200 here.
比如说 背景的灰度值为100 而这里的灰度值是200
Okay? So we already have seen that if we do a
所以我们已经知道 如果我们
small representation of our image we're going to be able to compress a lot.
用一种巧妙的方法表示图像的话 我们可以把图像压缩很多
As my representation means lets give to half on codeine very nice distributions,
巧妙的表示方法是指为霍夫曼编码提供分布良好的
very simple things and hopefully less than we will get by encoding the whole
非常简洁的数据 所需数据量有望比编码整幅图像更少
thing. So of course we could encode this image
当然我们可以编码整幅图像
by saying many times one hundred for the first row, same for the second row, and
通过多次重复灰度值100来表示第一行 第二行也一样
so on and so on. And imagine that this is you know 10,000.
同理表示整幅图像 想象这是一幅 10,000 x 10,000 大小的图像
by 10000 image. So, we're going to say 10,000 times 100,
我们对于像素值100 就要重复 10,000次
and we keep going. A smarter way, is basically to do the
然后以此类推 一个更巧妙些的方法如下所示
following. To say okay, let's just count how many
我们只要计算这儿有多少灰度值为100的像素
times they reach the value of 100. Let's just count how many times there is
接下来再计算有多少个灰度值为200的像素
the value 200. And let's count then after that how many
然后继续计算其后灰度值100又出现了多少次
times there is again the value 100. Basically this count we don't have to do
最后一次计算其实没必要做
if we know that there is only one transition.
如果已经知道图像只有一种灰度变化的话
So we count these and let's say that there is basically 3,000 times.
我们计算这些次数 假定在这里出现了3,000次
3000 times the value 100. So we still have encoding 3,000 times
3,000次灰度值为100的像素 与其编码3,000次100
100, we encode this value. And then let's assume that there is a
不如我们只编码这个值 接下来我们假设
1,000 times. Again, the value 200, so we put.
这里灰度值200出现了1,000次
3,000 then we put 1,000 and we're done, if we assume that it was only one object,
所以我们记下3,000和1,000 编码就完成了 前提是图像中只有一个物体
one transition. If not, we can keep going.
和一种灰度变化 如果不是上述情况 我们可以继续编码
So, by two numbers, we have encoded the whole row.
于是 只用两个值 我们便编码了一整行图像
And then we go to the next one, and we do the same.
然后进入下一行 我们用同样的方法编码
And this is called run-length coding, because it basically enclosed the run of
这就是游程编码 因为该方法编码的是相同数值所占的行程长度
equal numbers. We actually, indirectly, have seen that
实际上我们已经在 JPEG 中间接地见过它了
in JPEG already when we were in the transformed domain of JPEG and eight by
就在 JPEG 过程的变换域中 处理 8 × 8 的模块时
eight. I'm just drawing a part of this.
我只画出这部分的图示
And I say to you, I explain to you that when everything becomes zero, there is a
我解释过 当所有的值都变成 0
code that says, end of block. That's basically encoding by basically
会有一个码字标示数据块的结束 即只需一个值进行编码
one number, everything that is going to happen, to the end.
就可以搞定从头到尾的所有数据
And that's a basic idea of run length coding, again very useful for images, in
这就是游程编码的基本思想 我想再次强调游程编码非常有用
particular for, basically, geometric images,
特别是用于 几何图像
binary images, and indirectly was using JPEG but is very popular here.
二值图像和间接用于 JPEG过程 并在二值图像广泛应用
And even if we have more than one object and an area over here basically call the
即使我们有一个以上的物体 这里还有一个
runs. We say how many times there is 100? How
我们称之为行程 我们指明灰度值100出现多少次
many times 200? How many times again 100? How many time again 200 or any other
灰度值200出现多少次 100又出现了多少次 然后200又出现多少次 或者是其它需要的数值
value if needed. We encode the value and how many times it
我们对这些值和它们出现的次数进行编码
appears and with that we basically compress a lot.
通过这种编码方法我们能很大程度的进行压缩
This very, very simple images that otherwise would take us a very, very long
否则这个非常简单的图像会耗费非常长的编码来表示
codes to represent. And as before we could just encode these
如之前所说 我们可以仅编码这些值
numbers, as they are, or we could flag them in, into Huffman coding, and
就像这样 或者将它们用霍夫曼编码再次处理
basically compress them even further. With this, we basically complete the week
进一步压缩 通过游程编码的学习 我们完成了本周
on image and video compression. And now we have images, now we can
图像和视频压缩的课程 现在我们有了图像
receive images from, every place. We can compress, we can store.
我们可以从任意地方接收图像 也可以对图像进行压缩和存储
Next week we're going to start to process them.
下一周我们将开始处理这些图像
And what happens when basically our images are not as, they don't look as
并且了解为何我们的图像看上去并没有我想的那么好
nice as I wanted them to look? So that's what starts next week.
这些就是下周会讲到的内容
See you next week. Thank you.
下周见 谢谢大家 //果壳教育无边界字幕组 | 某音某莹 | 风过成伤 | 小白_远游